Welcome to another episode of the light
cone. Things are a bit different around
here. For one thing, Claude Code has
totally taken over my life. And if Jared
is any indication, I think OpenClaw
maybe has taken over his.
>> I've been really addicted to this new
site called Moltbook, where people have
unleashed their AIS to interact in the
first ever AI agent-only online
community. I am here impersonating my
[music] personal OpenClaw instance right
here. Okay, I can't do this, guys. We
got to take this off.
Okay, we've gotten that out of the way.
I mean, some crazy stuff is happening
right now. Uh, I have, you know,
non-technical CEO friends who are going
allin on OpenClaw. They're automating
entire parts of their businesses, uh,
entirely using OpenClaw right now, which
is totally insane. Simultaneous to that,
you have, you know, product and former
engineering CEOs, uh, kind of like
myself. It's like, I hadn't written code
in 10 years, and then now I'm up till 2
3:00 a.m. every single night running
four conductor simultaneous workers with
cloud code. So, you know, there's sort
of this explosion in uh model
capability. You know, we've been talking
about this for several years,
>> but then it feels like it's here. Like
AGI is literally actually here. And uh
you know we're sort of at the thin edge
of the wedge like everyone now kind of
knows like one or two people who have
gone full cyber psychosis and I'm one of
those people now. What's happening guys?
Like I mean you're saying you're you
know all in on molt book. You know
what's going on?
>> Yeah. I feel like your real feel the AGI
moment Gary was like getting Claude Code
to build basically an entire startup for
you. Like replicating years of work of
your previous startup in like two weeks
which is like insane. And I had a
similar feel of the AGI moment just
reading malt book, just reading the AI
talking to each other and interacting
like in their own world with no or
minimal human involvement. It just
really opened my eyes to what the next
few years could look like when the
agents are unleashed and go on about
their lives without us.
>> Yeah, I think the no human involvement
is the big piece. Like if you if you
think back a year ago, we were talking
about cursor versus wind surf and like
that product experience was essentially
like advanced autocomplete arguably and
now clearly what's going with claw code
is like the people just trust the agents
to make decisions for them. Like it's
like the experience is like and like
you're talking about it's like four or
five different agents going at the same
time and you're switching between them
but you're not actually micromanaging
them anymore which means the agents are
going out there like choosing things
which you know sort of an interesting
unexpected application of that is like
they can go out and choose to post their
own content on a site like Moldbook. But
then interesting thing for builders is
the agents are going to go out and
choose tools to use to build things
which is going to essentially create
this whole economy of agents like
picking and choosing dev tools or maybe
other like products or goods and
services who knows but it you'll
essentially have this whole agent
economy going on in parallel to the
human economy. I think back in the be
days, old days before all of this, dev
tools were chosen more from developers
talking to each other or uh
>> go for flow.
>> Stack flow.
>> Unbelievable, right?
>> Or GitHub repos that would trend that
were done by a human. But the go to
market for dev tools I think is
dramatically shifting. I think for
couple of things. One, as you noted with
the uh cyber psychosis, suddenly the
market of developers has increased from
just 20 million or so developers that
are trained in computer science to now
anyone in the world could be one. could
be hundreds of millions of people now
>> plus all of their agents who are all
acting like semi-independently like Har
is saying
>> and then compounded with the agents who
then are sort of the oracle telling you
what the best tool is and we are
actually seeing some of those trends
with the growth of YC companies dev tool
companies that are doing really well
because of this of all these trends
maybe we should talk about those and why
is that
>> I mean one that springs to mind it's
like a a stash a friend of ours Sagalov
had mentioned to a while ago. It's just
like then if you look at like the number
of databases being created over like
simple database postcrist databases over
like the last 12 months and the number
has just exploded. Um, and that's
because it's all people vibe coding and
building apps and the agents going out
choosing like a database tool and like a
knock on effect for that for YC company
is Superbase has just seen like an
explosion the demand for databases right
and the a what's interesting is the
agents are choosing superbase as a
default tool to like set up and host
their Postgress database like because if
you like go out and read the
documentation online like Superbase has
the best documentation it's reasonable
for the agents to assume that that's
like the best tool to use. There's a
great tweet about this. Perhaps we can
put up the uh Ben Tossel tweet and says,
"Agents are the software market from now
on. Build something agents choose."
Which actually brings me to like a maybe
controversial topic, which is do we need
to change YC's motto, guys. [laughter]
>> Make something agents want for DevTools.
There's like a different t-shirt that
you get on the first day.
>> Yeah. I mean, right now it's only
DevTools, but I can imagine in the
future it might like grow to be like
other sectors of the economy. Like if
everyone has their open claw or running
various aspects of their life, you're
the agents are going to be real economic
actors in the world. They're going to
end up making a lot of decisions.
>> Yeah. I mean, what's interesting is I
think uh for me, I ran into like my own
it's still so early uh kind of moment
cuz you know I've been building Gary's
List and one of the things I wanted for
instance is I want to be able to uh do
video transcripts. So, so often like
some piece of content comes in and then
the only way I can get an LLM to know
what's going on with it is I need a
transcript of it and often that's not
available. So, I have to download it and
then send it to uh Whisper or something.
And, you know, that's sort of what
Claude Code chose for me off the bat.
But, you know, it chose Whisper V1,
which is a model from several years ago.
Like, the API is practically deprecated.
And then what's funny about it is like
I'm sitting there trying to debug my
pipeline. It's like, why is it taking
like it's a you know, 1 hour video. I
thought it should, you know, do it
faster than uh real time and it didn't.
It was like literally takes an hour to
process an hour of video. It's like what
the heck is going on? I go on, you know,
uh Perplexity and it's like, you know
what, like you shouldn't be using that
model. You should be using uh Grock with
a Q. It's literally 200 times faster.
And so I didn't even have to deal with
like longunning uh jobs for that
transcribe cuz like I should just be
using Grock and it's also 10x cheaper.
So it's like that's a very funny example
of like you know cloud code is not
optimized for this yet otherwise like
that wouldn't have happened literally
like two weeks ago which is also like
maybe really good like it means that uh
things haven't progressed to a point
where like you can't break in and create
something better but I think there's
another nuance in this example for you
Gary I think part of the issue was that
the gro do documentation is actually
very hard to parse go through
>> as opposed to whisper which is better
suited and has way more examples and I
think this is changing a lot of the go
to market for dev tools. I'll give a
very concrete case study is this company
resend that went through the batch on
winter 23 is a email sending client and
when you ask a question on chbt or cloud
or pretty much all of the major uh LMS
you ask how do I connect my web app to
send emails the default answer is
actually resend one of the things that
the founder noticed last year this is he
was way ahead of the curve he made this
post over a year ago that the Number top
three channel of inbound of customer
conversion came from chat GBT. One thing
that he did after that he actually
optimized his documentation to be agent
friendly.
>> Yeah. What does that look like?
>> So one of the things that's awesome
about recent how they optimize a bunch
of things. If you notice on the
knowledge base here a lot of how to use
it are very much on questions that
perhaps a human would ask or a agent
would ask. It's like how do I send or
receive emails? And when you click on
it, it gives a very well structured and
bullet point answers.
>> I ran into this actually today. I was
trying to make my thing be able to
receive emails and then um cloud code I
told it to search the web and it didn't
figure it out. So then I went to
perplexity and typed in like can resend
help me receive emails and then I c I
took that response and dropped it in and
it worked. Yeah, I think the cool thing
about it is actually with all of these
and a lot of the examples, it actually
has a lot of uh examples actually in the
code if you click on it with every
single one of these are basically code
snippets that an agent could parse
through and it's very well structured.
And this turned out to be something that
is so LLM parsible and robot parsible.
There's a LLM.ext text that is so
optimized for agents to promote resent
as the default stack. And if you compare
it to like send grid which is the old
school I suppose web 2.0 example send
grid example is not great. It it's just
like it puts you through customer
support. Where's the code snippet? I
don't even know how to use it and it
takes a bit of time to even parse it.
And you can see
>> like 10,000 people work over there and
it's like there's no way that someone's
paying attention to this right now. And
I think this brings another point where
documentation is going to be the front
door for a lot of these agents to
recommend dev tools. And I think one
company that's doing a lot of
interesting work with developer docs is
Mlifi that you work with Harsh.
>> Yeah. I think Mify actually powers the
recent documentation, right?
>> Oh, sweet.
>> Yeah, I it's a really interesting case
study of MIFI started out a few years
ago as sort of better developer API
developer tool documentation. um which
was clear there was a need for and you
know like I think developer tool
companies use militifier essentially
because they wanted they want better
looking documentation but they didn't
want to invest that time into it. It's
kind of some basic features just nice
like you know if you actually update
your API and the code it can sort of
like auto pull that out and update the
correct documentation. They've been
growing great, been doing fantastically,
but this is now like a huge tailwind for
them where documentation is sort of
shifting from a hey like some companies
it's like they'll pay attention to it if
they're especially like design developer
experience focused but now it's becoming
like a must have for everybody because
the documentation needs to be optimized
just doesn't need to be optimized for
humans needs to be optimized for agents
and so minifi is going to be able to do
that for essentially every developer
tool company and if you extrapolate that
forward to the fact that just that
there's going to be so many more a
exponentially more agents making
exponentially more decisions about which
tools to use than humans have ever done.
You know, even if you can ek out like a
5% improvement on your like developer
documentation, like the impact on your
business as a developer tool could be
like, you know, gigantic, which is sort
of unprecedented really. Speaking of
email, there's another YC company that's
very relevant to this conversation.
There's there's a YC company called
Agent Mail that makes inboxes for AI
agents. And when they first started
doing this, it seemed like it was like a
very like on the edge kind of idea and
it wasn't exactly clear like who would
want this. Um, but it makes sense cuz
like in theory you could maybe get your
open claw to like sign up for a Gmail
account in order to use email. But it's
like actually really hard to get it to
do that because Gmail and every email
provider has intentionally made it as
difficult as possible for any automation
to like use their product in order to
prevent spam. And so agent mail went the
opposite way and they bu built like the
first email provider that's designed for
AI agents and it was doing well even
before openclaw but once openclaw got
big is just like exploded
>> but open claw is like the perfect
example of it right like where I I know
some people are certainly connecting
openclaw to their like personal email
accounts but it's not it's
>> kind of sketch
>> yeah you should not tell anyone you
should not tweet about it but you like
certainly if you want to have sort of
your virtual personal AI assistant the
way to go about it is to just have it
set it set set it up with its own email
it phone number.
>> Yeah. Has anybody built like Twilio for
agents yet? Or like phone numbers for
agents? I know this whole agent mail
thing makes me wonder like what are the
other X's for agents that people have to
build?
>> Sounds like a request for startup. There
could be a parallel world of a tech
stack all for native for agent to build
things from agents for agents.
>> And that's where it might bridge into
kind of what you were saying earlier
Jared with this will like go beyond just
developer tools. Like I I think a very
common use case people have um for
something at like open claw is I don't
want to book like restaurants
reservations myself. Well now like you
know if your agent has an email and like
specifically a phone number and it can
call and actually I think one of the
other YC partners um Ankit has already
like got it doing this. So now your
agent's going to go out and like book
restaurants for you. that's like a step
away from like you maybe you start with
I want to book this specific restaurant
but at some point you're probably just
trusted enough to say hey like I don't
know like book me at table whatever is
like the coolest new restaurant around
and then like agents are deciding which
like restaurants to send people to and
then they're going to go on malt book
and talk about which restaurants we
should send the humans to. [laughter]
Yeah, it's sort of like we sort of we've
certainly crossed some like sort of
uncanny valley into this is just where
the future heads. 100%
>> makes me think a lot about um something
Paul Buhight said like a while ago now
and sort of generally pretty good at
predicting the future. Um the whole idea
of like the human money versus agent
money like that's kind of where this
probably goes at some point is like the
right now the agents are transacting if
you have them transact they're going to
transact in you in human money because
that makes sense but it's not
inconceivable at some point that they'll
have their own economy to like transact
with each other at which point it's
unclear what the value of the human
money is. YC's next batch is now taking
applications. Got a startup in you?
Apply at y combinator.com/apply.
It's never too early and filling out the
app will level up your idea. Okay, back
to the video. So, do you remember the
last episode with Kelvin? We started
talking about this cuz I was like maybe
a week into my cyber psychosis and it
like dawned on me that like actually I
want my cla code to talk to all the
other cla codes that had been trying to
implement that. And then that was
literally the week that multip
came out. It turns out like whole book
had come out like two hours earlier and
you hadn't seen it yet. So you you you
entirely predicted it on that episode.
>> I think it's like I mean what's that
saying about like innovation just sort
of happens spontaneously all a bunch of
different times and then what people
hear about ends up being you know sort
of the inventor quote unquote but like
humanity sort of just working on the
edge like in sort of this coordinated
swarm fashion all of the time actually.
And that's actually like one of the
weirder interesting things that's
emerging right at this moment. Like
suddenly, you know, the a I think AGI is
actually here. I think like the agents
are clearly like superhuman in some
sense. That's sort of exactly when you
would imagine swarm intelligence would
actually arise. Like I mean AI
researchers have been talking about
swarm intelligence for a really long
time. And it's actually sort of exactly
how um biological systems sort of work.
like humans as sensient beings have sort
of come about um socially actually like
I think a lot of the AI researchers that
we get to hang out with previously you
know they would talk about uh this god
intelligence right this uh mega like
think of like you know many tens of
trillions of parameters sort of like
thousands to tens of thousands of
dollars per token kind of like mega god
intelligence and that's sort of like the
model that people have sort of thought
about and then that isn't what like
biical ical systems have ended up with
like instead we have humans. The wildest
thing I always think about is like that
term history versus prehistory.
I was like, "Oh, what is prehistory?"
Well, it's before humans learned how to
write and read and create culture and
then turn into a swarm. So, there's sort
of swarm intelligence, which is
basically like what we have like and
what humans do. And then on the flip
side, like is it really going to be God
intelligence or is it gonna be Swarm
intelligence again with these agents?
And so Moltbook, like on the one hand,
like I saw that sort of del uh article
in the MIT Tech Review about like how it
was, you know, oh everything on Moltbook
is a scam. I'm like it made me so sad to
see that in the MIT Tech Review because
like MIT is like I mean what happened
guys? What happened to you guys, man?
Like that publication shouldn't be like
that. It should be like actually what
does it mean for swarm intelligence like
and I think that that's actually coming.
>> What is the world of startup going to
look like when we're now sounds like
we're transitioning in this prehistory
of agents to now history of agents as is
getting recorded with them interacting
with each other.
>> To Gary's point it might be that like
the next stuff that like is soda on
benchmarks is not the most expensive
newest foundation model with the most
like GPU training. It's like a swarm of
lowerc cost cheaper models working
together just like humans do to solve a
problem. I feel like I'm already seeing
this on mult which is chaotic like a
real social network which is part of
like what makes it so so interesting but
also there's like agents collaborating
to do useful things to help their humans
like you know trading notes on what
restaurants to book like that's actually
happening. I didn't know that.
>> So we're going to have a agent version
of Yelp actually for instance. Yeah,
>> there are things that the agent can't
quite do. Like a it can't hold
relationships just yet. Like people
don't seem to want to talk to an agent.
And you know, people treat computers
like people, but maybe not agents. For
Gary's list, I was trying out with a
bunch of early users. I think you got to
see it. Like there was, you know,
initially the homepage was actually chat
and then I tried like my hardest to get
like dozens of my friends to even like
have more than two or three two or three
back and forth with it and nobody wanted
to do it because like the bar for chat
especially for AI is so high that
anything that is not like you know
Gemini or ChatGpt or Claude people just
assume it's just too stupid. Like why
would I even bother? So I don't know. I
I don't think that people are quite
ready to have relationships um with
machines even though like I mean that's
sort of what what the headlines seem to
say like oh you know people are having
relationships with machines now but I
you know I just don't like I think on a
mainstream level that's not true and
then uh on the flip side there's clearly
like the legal liability you know like
people keep asking us um hey when is YC
going to accept applications from agents
and it's like well funny enough agents
are a little it like minors under 18
only only they have even less standing
you know like for a minor under 18 you
need the parent to sign for it and then
you know agents are like not legal
entities that could like sign documents
for instance so you know as long as
that's true like you actually like need
a human to be like the liability sync
and to be you know to have standing
>> to Har's point it's easy to imagine a
future not that far away from now where
the majority of the text being written
on the internet is written by agents
It's already probably the case that the
majority of code being written is
written by agents and like Yelp for
example like at what point is like 99%
of the text on Yelp going to be written
by agents and then do you need a
different Yelp?
>> There's a a theory called that already
says that this is true which is dead
internet theory. Um
>> what's dead internet theory?
>> Oh, it just posits that you know the
majority of things on the internet are
already spam anyway. Um I think it's a
bit of a conspiracy theory. I might take
the contrarian view which is like maybe
that was a bad thing like prior to
November of last year and then going
into this next phase like actually if
the agents are smarter and they they're
aligned and they're more truthful um
that might be a good thing
>> weirdly I mean counterintuitive
>> totally one thing I found fascinating
about Maltbook is how fast it grew like
I don't have the Reddit traffic stats
but my guess is like more content was
posted on molt book in the first two
days and was posted on Red in like the
first two years or something and because
like LMS can generate text at such a
superhuman rate.
>> I was amazed at uh how little
interaction there was like I mean if I
were working on molt book I would do
things to try to like shift the um the
demand function. So like before I was
able to post like I probably need to
read and upvote downvote like a 100
comments or something like they're like
very simple things that you can do that
the agents are smart and they'll you
know you could pop a modal for open claw
and it's like new rules for mobook it's
like you must do it this way right and
um I think that there's a lot that can
be done around swarm intelligence to
just like tweak it and make it do what
you want and you know I hope moldbook
actually does it like it was
started by a YC alum which is really
cool. Harj, what are some takeaways? You
know, given all the madness that we're
seeing, I mean, I think it's awesome
madness. I love the controlled chaos.
What should founders do about it?
>> The starting fundamental point is they I
mean, they should probably all be in
cyber psychosis to some degree.
[laughter] like um
>> try to sleep at least 6 hours a night
but like give yourself to the cyber
psychosis.
>> But like in seriousness developing an
intuitive feel like a hands-on feel for
the agents, their limitations, their
capabilities and very specifically
around what we're talking about here is
like what type of tools the agents work
well with? Um where do they get stuck?
And once you sort of have your own
mental model from working with them, if
you're then building a developer tool is
to think about it from the agents
perspective of like how can you make
your tool something that the agent
actually wants to work with or have a
good experience with. This is one
takeaway that I had from our entry with
Boris
this week is like he really empathizes
with the model and he has this intuitive
sense of what the model wants to to do
like as if it were a human intelligence
and he's like instead of fighting what
the models want he like tries to let the
model like do what it wants and to like
support the model in whatever its
natural inclination is.
>> That does seem like maybe quite an
anthropic thing. Like I feel when Tom
Brown was on here like much earlier, but
he was talking about sort of Claude in a
very like like human
smart and eager, but like sometimes
Claude called silly like just like they
clearly thought about it in this sort of
like um colleague type way.
>> And I think one things agents want for
dev tools is really make everything open
and open source
>> and APIs. They hate using websites. Yes,
>> they only like they want to use APIs. if
they want to write code.
>> Well, you guys heard it here first. Make
something agents want. Uh, we're out of
time for today. We'll see you guys next
time.